

I'm a backend software developer specialized in Python and Kotlin, with experience in identity validation and devexp solutions. I'm a person who can lead a team to succeed in any project and likes to help others achieve their goals.



## **CONTACT INFO**

Email: ake.giraldo@gmail.com

LinkedIn: /in/akegiraldo



## **EDUCATION / SKILLS**

## **Backend developer**

**Holberton School** 

Sep. 2019 - Jul. 2022

#### **Software engineer**

Politécnico Colombiano Jaime Isaza Cadavid

Feb. 2016 - Nov. 2019

### **Programming languages and tools**

Languages: Python, Kotlin, Java

Frameworks: Springboot, Flask, Fastapi

SQL: Postgresql, MySQL, Oracle

**NoSQL:** Redis, MongoDB **Streaming:** Apache Kafka

Cloud: AWS, Docker, Jenkins, ArgoCD

Others: GIT, Linux

# KEVIN ADRIÁN GIRALDO V

BACKEND DEVELOPER



## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Backend developer**

Tül, May 2022 - Present

I work in the devexp team where we design and develop solutions that can be implemented by the rest of the teams in the company.

- I am in charge of the development and implementation of backend libraries that can be used in various microservices.
- We developed a platform to optimize processes like managing microservices, secrets and environments.

#### **Backend developer**

#### **Rappi, August 2020 - May 2022**

I worked in the identity area where we developed machine-learning solutions to validate people's identities.

- I was in charge of maintaining the stability of my team's microservices in 9 countries.
- Designed and planned the backend tasks for each sprint according to the SCRUM methodology.
- Developed and maintained services using Python and Kotlin languages; frameworks like Flask, Faust, SpringBoot and Apache Kafka; databases like Redis and SQL and tools like Docker, Jenkins and Git.



## **CERTIFICATES**

EFSET English Certificate 72/100 (C2 Proficient)

**Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate** (SFPC)